A software engineer having 6+ years of experience, currently seeking a backend-engineer position. My expertise is to research and design software solutions for complex mathematical and business problems. Looking to make positive contribution to the society.

EDUCATION

National University of Computer and Emerging Sciences

Karachi

BS Computer Science, CGPA 3.03/4.0

2012 - 2016

EXPERIENCE

Seed Labs

Karachi

Sr Software Engineer

Oct 2021 - Present

• Firefly: Writing code for a fast and low-fee decentralized financial exchange.

Folio3 Software

Karachi

Sr Software Engineer

Nov 2019 - Sep 2021

- Netsuite ERP Customization: Business process design and customizations with Suitescript and React.
- $\circ \ \ \textbf{Ecommerce Connector} : \ Development \ of \ a \ connector \ that \ integrates \ Oracle \ Net suite \ with \ e-commerce \ systems.$

• Ivolve Technologies Sr Software Engineer

Karachi Jul 2019 - Nov 2019

- Hybrid-cloud Middleware: Took part in the integration of Openstack with other public cloud services.
- Monitoring system: Developed a monitoring solution for Openstack's cloud using tools including Ceilometer, Gnocchi, Elasticsearch, Graphite and Grafana.

Cloud9 Networks FZE

Dubai

Software engineer

Jul 2016 - Jun 2019

- Cloud Monitoring Software:
 - * Developed a logging, monitoring and alerting system for Openstack cloud.
 - * Integrated a telemetry system for Openstack cloud.
- Network Monitoring System:
 - * Development of a network monitoring system that monitors thousands of customer premises equipment: collects and stores metrics. Built monitoring dashboards for data visualization and integrated alerting and ticketing systems.
- o Big Data Analytics Engine:
 - * Developed a REST API in Java Spring and frontend in AngularJS.
 - * Designed and deployed a Hadoop cluster and created BIRT reports from HIVE. Created Oozie jobs to schedule HIVE scripts.
- o PNDA Project:
 - * Deployed PNDA Big data network analytics toolchain on Openstack cloud.

FAST-NUCES Research Assistant

Karachi

Jan 2015 - Jun 2016

- Research Assistant Machine Learning: Research on puzzle solving using various data-driven techniques. Applied deep learning algorithms on puzzle solutions generated from Copris Theorem Prover. http://dx.doi.org/10.14569/IJACSA.2017.080364
- Systems Engineer Nvidia HPC Lab of FAST NUCES: Designed and deployed a Message Passing Interface(MPI) and Hadoop cluster for HPC class of fall-2015.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- **Programming**: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Java, C++, Rust.
- Web: Node.js, React, Flask, HTML, CSS.
- Libraries: Pandas, Numpy, Nvidia CUDA, SuiteScript.
- Databases: MySQL, Postgres, MongoDB, Elasticsearch, Graphite, Influxdb, Hadoop, Apache Hive.
- Data visualization: Grafana, Kibana, BIRT.
- Network monitoring: Prometheus, Elasticsearch, Nagios, Icinga.
- Automation: Github Actions, Puppet, SaltStack.
- Cloud: Openstack, AWS EC2, GCP, Kubernetes, Netsuite SuiteCloud ERP.